Soohwan Kim

18F, Seocho-daero 74 The Asset Tower, Seocho-District, Seoul, South Korea

2 (+82)10-4564-4668 sh951011@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/Soo-hwan/

github.com/sooftware

OBJECTIVE

Ambitious A.I. research engineer with 2+ years experience in speech and natural language processing fields. Currently, co-founder of a tech startup named TUNiB, research interests includes speech processing, natural language processing, and MLOps. In particular, recently been very interested in large-scale language model training and big-data processing.

EDUCATION

Kwangwoon University

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication

Mar. 2014 - Feb 2021

Seoul, South Korea

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

• Machine Learning

• System Programming • Database

• Data Structures

• Operating System

• Data Mining

• Computer Architecture

Professional Experience

• Digital Signal Processing

TUNiB, Inc

Mar 2021 - Present

Gangnam, Seoul

Co-founder/A.I. Engineer

Co-founded with former Kakao Brain team members.

- Developing large-scale language model and open-domain dialogue system.
- Lead the development of the TUNiB Electra model, data construction, modeling, and experimental design.
- 1st ranked in the 2021 AI Online Competition, attracting 300 million won worth of subsidies.

Kakao Brain, Corp

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021 Pangyo, Gyunggi

A.I. Engineer

• Team Leader: Kyubyong Park

- Developed a open-source natural language processing library named pororo
- Developed multilingual TTS technology. Demo page: https://pororo-tts.github.io/
- Developed English, Chinese, and Korean speech recognition using Wav2vec 2.0 technology.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Open-domain Dialogue System | NLP, DeepSpeed, Transformers, Megatron-LM

Apr 2021 - Present

- Research and develop various versions of chatbots.
- Participate in the development of all overall systems from data construction to big model training.

TUNIB Electra | NLP, Transformers, Tokenizers, TPU, Google Cloud Platform

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021

- Released two version of ELECTRA models. (Korean-English bilingual model, Korean-only model).
- Conducted performance comparison experiments between several tokenizers made using the Tokenizers library.

Pororo | NLP, Fairseq, PyTorch

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

- Library that can solve more than 30 natural language processing tasks in just 3-4 lines with pre-trained models.
- Developed speech related modules. (Automatic Speech Recognition, Text To Speech)

OpenSpeech/KoSpeech | ASR, PyTorch-Lightning, Hydra

Jan 2020 - Jun 2021

- Framework that enables easy creation of speech recognition models of various models and various languages.
- Dozens of models including Transformers, ContextNets, Transformers, and Listen Attend Spell.

Awards & Honors

- 2021.08 NIPA President's Award (1st ranked), 2021 AI Online Competition
- 2020.11 President's Award (1st ranked) & People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon Engineering Festival
- 2020.10 3rd ranked, 2020 AI Grand Challenge Speech Recognition Track
- 2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship
- 2019.10 Finalist (12th Ranked), Naver AI Hackathon Speech
- 2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwang University Software Start-up Idea Contest
- 2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship
- 2018.08 Outstanding Award, Samsung Multi-Campus